

RAMÓN IVÁN PUÓN MERAZ

CONTACT DETAILS

- Linkedin Profile
- 9616103856
- ramon.puon@gmail.com
- Location: Mexico

SKILLS

- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
 - Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- HTML, CSS,
 Javascript
- React Library
- Webpack
- R (Bioconductor)

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native
- English C1 -Advanced

RELEVANT COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to Data Science in Python, Coursera
- Python for Genomic Data Science, Coursera
- Data Manipulation and Analysis with Pandas and Python , Platzi
- Frontend Developer
 Practical Course, Platzi
- React.js Practical Course, Platzi
- Javascript Practical Course, Platzi
- Webpack course, Platzi

PROFILE

Self-taught and highly motivated **data scientist**, focusing in writing clear and concise code. Interest in implementing my knowledge in statistics, and research experience, to turn data into useful business insights.

For more info, visit my personal Web Portfolio

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Radiohead Data Analysis

Using the python library spotipy, you can extract data from the Spotipy API. An analysis of the audio features of the Radiohead catalogue was performed using pandas and seaborn for data visualization. Work in progress

RoadTrip Map Chiapas.

Website set up to represent a guide with tourist sites in the state of Chiapas, in Mexico. Built with HTML, CSS, React, and the Javascript library Leaflet. Work in progress.

Cumbres Blancas Website

Contributions to the implementation of web design for the site of the Mexican organization Cumbres Blancas, an environmental NGO.

RELATED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Development Personal Projects.

September 2021 — Current (4 months)

I am currently developing projects, with the aim of adapting to using the latest frontend tools and obtaining experience in data visualization and analysis.

Data Visualization of Environmental Microbiology Project

August 2019 — June 2021 (2 years)

Implementation of python library matplotlib to present results in master's thesis project. Statistical analysis of these results was carried out in Minitab.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN BIOTECHNOLOGY INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO Y DE ESTUDIOS SUPERIORES DE MONTERREY (ITESM), PUEBLA

August 2019 — June 2021

Thesis Project: "Characterization of the chromium reduction activity of an endemic bacterium from the Atoyac river with potential use in water bioremediation"

BIOTECHNOLOGY ENGINEERING INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO Y DE ESTUDIOS SUPERIORES DE MONTERREY (ITESM), PUEBLA

January 2015 — June 2019